export const CHEMISTRYA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The hydrolysis of proteins by dilute mineral acids produces",
A: "sucrose",
B: "glucose",
C: "amino acids",
D: "fatty acids",
answer: "C. amino acids",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following oxides causes acid rain?",
A: "CO",
B: "NO",
C: "H2O",
D: "NO2",
answer: "D. NO2",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The ratio of carbon atoms to hydrogen atoms in a hydrocarbon is 1:2. If its molecular mass is 56, what is its molecular formula?",
A: "C3H6",
B: "C4H8",
C: "C2H4",
D: "CH2",
answer: "B. C4H8",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. What is the relative molecular mass of the compound below? [H= 1.0; C=12.0; O=16.0]",
A: "137",
B: "136",
C: "64",
D: "59",
answer: "B. 136",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Cathodic protection of metals is based on",
A: "standard electrode potential of hydrogen",
B: "its electrical conductivity",
C: "nature of oxides formed",
D: "relative tendencies of oxidation",
answer: "A. standard electrode potential of hydrogen",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. If humid air is polluted by chlorine discharge, the air can be restored by sprinkling",
A: "solid MnO2",
B: "acidified KMnO4",
C: "acidified FeSO4",
D: "saturated NaCl(aq)",
answer: "C. acidified FeSO4",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The alkanols represented by the structure below is",
A: "primary and dihydric",
B: "secondary and monohydric",
C: "tertiary and dihydric",
D: "secondary and dihydric",
answer: "C. tertiary and dihydric",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following pairs of compounds will form a precipitate when their aqueous solutions are mixed?",
A: "NaCl and KNO3",
B: "KCl and NaNO3",
C: "K2SO4 and BaCl2",
D: "NH4NO3 and Na2CO3",
answer: "C. K2SO4 and BaCl2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the graphs, in the options, illustrate the variation of the rate of evolution of a gas from a given length of magnesium ribbon (y-axis) with increase in the concentration of the acid added (x-axis)?",
A: "A",
B: "B",
C: "C",
D: "D",
answer: "D. zzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the graphs illustrate the variation of the pH of a given volume of strong acid solution (y-axis) with the volume of strong base titrated against it (x-axis)?",
A: "A",
B: "B",
C: "C",
D: "D",
answer: "D. zzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the graphs illustrate the variation of the solubility of a salt in water (y-axis) with increase in temperature (x-axis), if the dissolution process is exothermic?",
A: "A",
B: "B",
C: "C",
D: "D",
answer: "C. zzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The formation of ethene from dehydration of ethanol can be described as",
A: "an addition reaction",
B: "an elimination reaction",
C: "an oxidation reaction",
D: "a substitution reaction",
answer: "B. an elimination reaction",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following gasses is highly soluble in water at room temperature?",
A: "ammonia",
B: "carbon (IV) oxide",
C: "chlorine",
D: "nitrogen",
answer: "A. ammonia",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A molecule of phosphorus is",
A: "diatomic",
B: "triatomic",
C: "tetra atomic",
D: "monoatomic",
answer: "C. tetra atomic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The most common method of preparing insoluble salt is by",
A: "filtration",
B: "decomposition",
C: "neutralization",
D: "double decomposition",
answer: "D. double decomposition",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. What number of moles of oxygen will exert a pressure of 10 atmosphere at 320K in an 8.2dm3 cylinder? [R = 0.082atmdm3/mol/K]",
A: "0.32",
B: "1.56",
C: "3.13",
D: "31.25",
answer: "C. 3.13",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The basic property of salt used as drying agent is",
A: "efflorescence",
B: "high melting point",
C: "hydroscopy",
D: "low solubility",
answer: "C. hydroscopy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. What would be observed when aqueous ammonia is added in drops and then in excess to a solution of copper (II) ions?",
A: "blue precipitate is formed which is soluble in excess ammonia",
B: "brick red precipitate is produced which is insoluble in excess ammonia",
C: "white precipitate is formed which is soluble in excess ammonia",
D: "green precipitate is formed which is insoluble in excess ammonia",
answer: "A. blue precipitate is formed which is soluble in excess ammonia",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. When CuSO4(aq) is added to Pb(NO3)2(aq)",
A: "there will be no visible change",
B: "a blue precipitate will be formed",
C: "the resulting solution will become colourless",
D: "a white precipitate will be formed",
answer: "D. a white precipitate will be formed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. How many carbon atoms does the parent chain contain?",
A: "5",
B: "4",
C: "3",
D: "2",
answer: "B. 4",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Under which conditions of pressure (P) and temperature (T) would the volume of an inflated balloon increase? When",
A: "both T and P are increased",
B: "both T and P are decreased",
C: "T is increased and P is decreased",
D: "T is decreased and P is increased",
answer: "C. T is increased and P is decreased",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The collision between ideal gas molecules are considered to be perfectly elastic because",
A: "they collide without losing energy",
B: "they move randomly in a straight line",
C: "the average kinetic energy is variable",
D: "the distance between them is large compared to their sizes",
answer: "A. they collide without losing energy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Elements with high ionization energy would",
A: "lose electrons easily",
B: "have large atomic radii",
C: "have effectively nuclear charges",
D: "have low atomic number",
answer: "C. have effectively nuclear charges",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following statements about group VII elements is correct?",
A: "They are present in the same physical state",
B: "They are strong reducing agent",
C: "Their reactivity decreases down the group",
D: "They exist as monoatomic molecule",
answer: "C. Their reactivity decreases down the group",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following cell notations represents the diagram?",
A: "B2+/B//A/A3+",
B: "A3+/A//B/B2+",
C: "B/B2+//A/A3+",
D: "A/A3+//B2+/B",
answer: "D. A/A3+//B2+/B",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following half-reaction equations represent the reaction at the cathode?",
A: "A3+(aq)  +  3e–→ A(s)",
B: "B2+(aq)  +  2e–  → B(s)",
C: "A(s) → A3+(aq)  +  3e–",
D: "B(s) → B2+(aq)  +  2e–",
answer: "B. B2+(aq) + 2e– → B(s)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The reactivity of fluorine is high because of",
A: "its high electronegativity",
B: "the small size of the fluorine atom",
C: "the availability of d-orbitals",
D: "the strong F-F bond",
answer: "A. its high electronegativity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. How many coulombs of electricity would liberate 1.08g of Ag from a solution of silver salt? [Ag = 108.0; F = 96500 C]",
A: "96500 C",
B: "9650 C",
C: "965 C",
D: "9.65 C",
answer: "C. 965 C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The Bohr model of the atom proposed the existence of",
A: "the nucleus",
B: "electron shells",
C: "nucleons",
D: "neutrons",
answer: "B. electron shells",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. At 25 oC evaporation of a 100cm3 solution of K2CO3 to dryness gave 14g of the salt. What is the solubility of K2CO3 at 25°C? [K2CO3 = 138]",
A: "0.01 mol/dm3",
B: "0.101 mol/dm3",
C: "1.01 mol/dm3",
D: "10.0 mol/dm3",
answer: "C. 1.01 mol/dm3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following statements about the titration is true?",
A: "Hydrogen chloride gas was released in the reaction in both titration",
B: "The titre values obtained by the titrations are equal",
C: "The titre value obtained by X is twice that of Y",
D: "The titre value obtained by Y is twice that of X",
answer: "C . The titre value obtained by X is twice that of Y",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. What is the concentration of a solution which contains 0.28g of KOH in 100cm3 of solution? [KOH= 56]",
A: "0.01 mol/dm3",
B: "0.05 mol/dm3",
C: "0.10 mol/dm3",
D: "0.50 mol/dm3",
answer: "B. 0.05 mol/dm3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. What is the empirical formula of a hydrocarbon containing 0.160mol of carbon and 0.640 moles of hydrogen?",
A: "CH2",
B: "CH3",
C: "CH4",
D: "C2H4",
answer: "B. CH3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following species has the largest ionic radius?",
A: "S2-",
B: "Cl–",
C: "K+",
D: "Ca2+",
answer: "A. S2-",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following statements is correct about ionization energy?",
A: "Decreases across the period",
B: "Results in the formation of an anion",
C: "Causes metallic nuclei to disintegrate",
D: "Decreases down the group",
answer: "D. Decreases down the group",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Potassium trioxonitrate (V) can be obtained from its solution by",
A: "Distillation",
B: "Evaporation",
C: "Crystallization",
D: "Filtration",
answer: "C. Crystallization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. An element, Q, contains 69% of 63Q and 31% of 65Q. What is the relative atomic mass of Q?",
A: "63.0",
B: "63.6",
C: "65.0",
D: "69.0",
answer: "B. 63.6",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The following ions have the same electron configuration except 8O, 12Mg, 13Al, 17Cl.",
A: "Cl–",
B: "O2-",
C: "Mg2+",
D: "Al3+",
answer: "A. Cl–",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The region around the nucleus where electrons can be located is called",
A: "spectra",
B: "an orbital",
C: "a quanta",
D: "a field",
answer: "B. an orbital",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Protons and electrons are fundamentals particles because they",
A: "are invisible",
B: "have different charges",
C: "are the lightest particles",
D: "are found in all matter",
answer: "D. are found in all matter",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The activation energy of the reaction is",
A: "EA",
B: "EB",
C: "EC",
D: "ED",
answer: "B. EB",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The enthalpy change of the reaction is",
A: "EA",
B: "EB",
C: "EC",
D: "ED",
answer: "D. ED",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The energy profile diagram illustrates",
A: "an endothermic reaction",
B: "an exothermic reaction",
C: "a spontaneous reaction",
D: "a redox reaction",
answer: "B. an exothermic reaction",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. How many molecules of oxygen would occupy a volume of 2.24 cm3 at S.t.p.?",
A: "3.01 x 1020",
B: "3.01 x 1027",
C: "6.02 x 1019",
D: "6.02 x 1027",
answer: "C. 6.02 x 1019",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The isotopes of neon are represented by the symbols 20xNe, 21yNe and 22zNe. The relationship between x, y and z is",
A: "x > y > z",
B: "x < y < z",
C: "x = y = z",
D: "x < z < y",
answer: "C. x = y = z",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following pairs of molecules form hydrogen bond?",
A: "C2H5OH and CH3OH",
B: "CH3OH and H2",
C: "H2S and CH4",
D: "NH3 and SO2",
answer: "A. C2H5OH and CH3OH",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following statements about elements in group VII is correct?",
A: "Br2 will oxidiza Cl–",
B: "F2 has the least tendency to be reduced",
C: "Cl2  will oxidize I–",
D: "I2 is a stronger oxidizing agent than F2",
answer: "D. I2 is a stronger oxidizing agent than F2",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Electrovalent compounds normally",
A: "have low boiling points",
B: "have high mobile electrons",
C: "conduct electricity in solid state",
D: "dissolve in polar solvents",
answer: "D. dissolve in polar solvents",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A coordinate covalent bond could be formed between",
A: "NH3 and PCl3",
B: "BCl3 and AlCl3",
C: "BCl3 and NH3",
D: "H+ and AlCl3",
answer: "D. H+ and AlCl3",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following scientists discovered the electron?",
A: "Joseph J. Thompson",
B: "James Chadwick",
C: "Amedeo Avogadro",
D: "Ernest Rutherford",
answer: "A. Joseph J. Thompson",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]